

# VIVEK KUMAR SINGH BLANALYST

#### **PROFILE**

7.5 years of total experience on various role in IT Industries with 5+ years on multiple Analytics BI Reporting tool and expertise in designing and implementing Relational Database model, creating Complex Spotfire, Power BI, Tableau Dashboards and sharing key trends and business insights to the client and helping them in effective business decisions

#### **CONTACT**



+91 9990176779

vivekvix2@gmail.com

### **SKILLS**



#### CERTIFICATION

- ➤ TIBCO® Certified Professional for TCP -TIBCO Spotfire® 7
- > Tableau Desktop Specialist



www.linkedin.com/in/vivekvix/





Tower lead

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**L'Oréal AMS Project** Sep 2017 – Present

Technology: Tibco Spotfire, Power BI, Tableau, Python, R, SQL,

As Tower lead I am involved in -

- Lead 5 member team to support the Reporting infrastructure and keep environment up and running.
- Understanding the existing reports and their backend data, upgrading them as per request.
- Aid in developing style guide for development of BI visualizations, design of components, naming of items, data source creation and naming using Best Practices, and Programming concepts.
- Interacting with user for reports and understanding there requirement with reports.
   Providing demos and solutions.
- Worked in Agile/Scrum environment to build weekly, monthly and quarterly progress reports through each release on Spotfire, PowerBI sharing key trends and business insights to the client and helping them in effective business decisions

GE Aviation. – Data Lake Project

May 2014 – May 2017

Technical Lead

Technology: Tibco Spotfire, Tableau, SQL, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Python, JSViz R, SQL,

As Technical Lead I was involved in -

- Technical Lead of 6 member team of Spotfire working on different modules.
- Understanding the existing cognos reports and their SQL queries, migrating them
  to Spotfire reports. Providing user friendly report designs utilizing inbuilt visualizations,
  HTML, CSS, JQuery, Python, JSViz.
- Designed SQL Queries from scratch to import data from Oracle DB to different views and created dashboards to monitor trends

Ecolab Inc. – Migration to Tibco BW

April 2013 – Feb 2014

Integration Developer

Technology: TIBCO BW, EMS, CA- API

As Integration developer I was involved in –

- Tibco BW and CA API gate to create Business to Business integration solution
- Implement requirements of the API layer like logging, request and response modifications etc. using CA API Gateway
- Understanding the old Gentran Mappings (Inbound & Outbound) and schemas, migrating them to TIBCO mappings.
- Analyzing/designing the specification documents, building the project using TIBCO suite applications, testing, packaging and monitoring the developed deliverables.

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Technology	2012	Gautam Buddh Technical University
Higher Secondary School	2007	Kendriya Vidyalaya
Secondary School	2005	Kendriya Vidyalaya

### **ORGANIZATIONS**

Wipro Limited Sep 2017 – Present Tata Consultancy Services Dec 2012 – Sep 2017

## **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

- Proficient with multiple Data Analysis and Business Intelligence Tools like Spotfire, Power BI, Tableau.
- Expert in data Analysis, Data Massaging and manipulation
- Knowledge on Consumer Product and Logistic Domains
- Strong experience in Data Visualization | Data Mining | Data Modeling | Predictive Modeling | Statistical Analysis. Skills - R, SQL, Python, Tableau, MS Excel,
- Working with large data set to handle and create useful insights
- ITIL certified
- Outstanding verbal and written communication skills rooted in transparency and collaboration
- Domain experience in Consumer Products, Aviation Finance, Logistics